Guide to the Silas Reed Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Silas Reed papers
1833-1886
WA MSS 399
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
4.2
(10 boxes)
The papers consist of diaries, 1872-81, recording Silas Reed's travels to and from Boston, Washington, and the West, letters and telegrams received, and family and business affairs. Correspondence and business papers, 1841-93, contain letters with the Anthony and Reed families and colleagues, tax and property documents, material, including maps, regarding mines and mining in Missouri and Utah, and financial papers.
Reed, Silas, 1807-1886
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of William Robertson Coe. Letter to John P. Thomas, 1873 August 11, and 1873 September 1, purchased from Robert H. Rubin Books on the Arthur Corbitt Hoskins Memorial Fund, 2012.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
SILAS REED (1807-1886)
Silas Reed was born in Ohio in 1807 and, after receiving a diploma from the Medical College of Ohio, lived in Cincinnati for several years. About 1838, Reed moved to Rock Island, Illinois, and in 1841 was appointed surveyor general of Illinois and Missouri by President William Henry Harrison. This appointment was not confirmed by the Senate, but after the presentation by Dr. Reed of letters and memorials to President John Tyler and the Senate, it was brought up again and approved. Dr. Reed served as surveyor general from March 17, 1841, to May 12, 1845, and continued to make his headquarters in St. Louis until 1870, when he was appointed the first surveyor general of Wyoming Territory by President Ulysses S. Grant. Due in part to political intrigue, he resigned in 1875 and devoted his remaining years to his mining interests in Utah and the promotion of the Dallas and Wichita Railroad Company in Texas. In 1876, he appeared before the Congressional Committee on Expenditures in the Interior Department in its investigation of surveys in the Territory of Wyoming. During the Civil War, Dr. Reed served as acting assistant surgeon in army hospitals in Tennessee and Missouri. He died in Utah on October 1 or 2, 1886.
Scope and Contents
The Silas Reed Papers (WA MSS 399) consist of diaries, correspondence, business and family papers, including maps and diagrams, written between 1833 and 1886. There are sixteen volumes in the collection.
Series I, Diaries, consists of twelve volumes, around 1,895 pages in all, and covering the dates January 1, 1872-August 29, 1874 and January 1, 1877-January 31, 1881. The diaries record Dr. Reed's trips to and from Boston and Washington and throughout the West. They include letters and telegrams received and sent, and brief references to business and family affairs.
The second and fourth series, Miscellaneous Business Papers and Miscellaneous Legal Papers include deeds (some of them forged), tax lists and receipts, and other documents relating to property in St. Louis and other parts of Missouri, as well as notes on mines and mining claims in Missouri and Utah, papers dealing with the Missouri Smelting and Mineral Lands Company, maps and diagrams, canceled drafts and notes, accounts, bills, and receipts.
The third series, Correspondence, includes Dr. Reed's letters to his wife, Henrieta Maria Rogers, written almost daily when they were separated, especially in 1872 and 1880-86, as well as letters to other members of the family. The letters to others are usually drafts or copies. Dr. Reed also obtained, by permission of the Senate, the original memorials and letters sent to Congress in his favor in 1841. The letters to his family give details of his business transactions, record the names of people he met, and provide news of political and local affairs, especially in Missouri and Wyoming. Reed's daughter, Clara James Reed, was the wife of Nathan Anthony, and the family correspondence includes letters to members of both the Reed and Anthony families from friends and relatives in the East as well as the letters of the Anthony family written between 1890 and 1893, after the death of Dr. Reed.
The fifth series consists of a Scrapbook of newspaper clippings in the collection. The book covers the dates 1837-86. The clippings are chiefly about Reed's appointment as surveyor general of Missouri and Illinois in 1841, the rejection of the appointment by the Senate and Reed's final confirmation, the investigation of his administration of the office, and the libel suit of the United States and James S. Conway (his successor as surveyor general) against Reed, editor of the St. Louis Morning Post, 1841-48.
The Appendices, An Alphabetical List of Correspondents and A List of Miscellaneous Documents of Silas Reed, can also be found on pp. 217-28 of A Catalogue of Manuscripts in the Collection of Western Americana in the Yale University Library, Mary C. Withington, editor.
Appendix A: Alphabetical List of Correspondents
Reed, Silas. 718 letters to his wife, Henrietta Maria Rogers. February 28, 1856-August 27, 1886. 2,602 pp. 67 postcards.
---- Letter to Beverly Allen. October 12, 1841. Draft. 1 p.
---- Letter to J. G. Anderson. February 21, 1873. Draft. 1 p.
---- Letter to W. J. Andrews. November 3, 1883. Draft. 2 pp.
---- 15 letters to his grandson, Arthur Cox Anthony. January 23, 1878- May 30, 1886. 54 pp.
---- 86 letters to his daughter, Clara James Reed (Mrs. Nathan Anthony). October 12, 1856-[June 23?], 1886. 322 pp.
---- 14 letters to his son-in-law, Nathan Anthony. December 3, 1866- September 25, 1880. 47 pp.
---- Eight letters to his grandson, Silas Reed Anthony. August 14, 1875- July 11, 1886. 33 pp.
---- Two letters to John Atkinson. May 19, October 11, 1881. Copies. 4 pp.
---- Letter to George Barry. May 13, 1886. Draft. 1 p.
---- Letter to Edward Bates. September 12, 1862. Draft. 1 p.
---- Letter to James G. Blaine. June 16, 1876. Draft. 1 p.
---- Letter to George Bliss. January 25, 1867. Draft. 2 pp.
---- Letter to George Sewel Boutwell. November 27, 1872. Copy. 4 pp.
---- Letter to Arthur Brown. March 25, 1881. Copy. 2 pp.
---- Letter to C. C. Cady. November 25, 1841. Copy. 2 pp.
---- Two letters to J. G. Cameron. October 30, November 8, 1841. Copies. 2 pp.
---- Letter to Grover Cleveland. March 26, 1886. Draft. 2 pp.
---- Letter to James D. Cleveland. June 15, 1869. Draft. 2 pp.
---- Four letters to Henry I. Coe. April 5, 1866-September 26, 1877, and a release, March 1, 1874. Copies. 7 pp.
---- Letter to J. B. Cooke. January 17, 1881. Copy. 1 p.
---- Letter to W. W. Curtis. May 25, 1874. Copy. 1 p.
---- Letter to Caleb Cushing. December 7, 1870. Copy. 2 pp.
---- Letter to John F. Darby. October 18, 1841. Copy. 1 p.
---- Letter to George C. Davis. October 29, 1872. Copy. 1 p.
---- Five letters and two telegrams to Columbus Delano. March 21, 1873- May 11, 1876. Copies. 9 pp.
---- Letter to J. S. Delano. June 14, [1873]. Copy. 2 pp.
---- Letter to Richard S. Dement. July 24, 1886. Copy. 2 pp.
---- Letter to Stephen W. Downey. April 22, 1873. Copy. 2 pp.
---- Eight letters and a telegram to Willis Drummond. March 27, 1873- November 14, 1881. Copies and drafts. 12 pp.
---- Letter to Cyrus Edwards. October 30, 1841. Copy. 1 p.
---- Letter to A. Eurgens. December 1, 1875. Draft. 1 p.
---- Letter to Thomas Ewing. August 22, 1841. Copy. 1 p.
---- Letter to the Rev. J. P. Farley. May 23, 1866. Copy. 2 pp.
---- Letter to Alpheus Felch. May 29, 1852. Copy. 4 pp.
---- Letter to Thomas W. Ferry. February 26, 1882. Copy. 5 pp.
---- Letter to George D. Foglesong. April 22, 1873. Copy. 2 pp.
---- Letter to J. O. Friend. February 3, 1870. Copy. 2 pp.
---- Letter to T. M. Fulton. July 6, 1875. Copy. 1 p.
---- Letter to J. E. Gallagher. January 12, 1882. Copy. 2 pp.
---- Letter to Hamilton R. Gamble. October 18, 1841. Copy. 1 p.
---- Two letters to his brother-in-law, Mason Gibbs. September 27, 1841, [June 4, 1843]. 3 pp.
---- Letter to H. Glafcke. January 29, 1876. Copy. 1 p.
---- Letter to Miss Nellie Grant. August 23, 1873. Copy. 2 pp.
---- Telegram and letter to Orville L. Grant. March 23, 25, 1873. Copies. 4 pp.
---- Letter to J. P. Green. November 17, 1875. Copy. 2 pp.
---- Letter to J. Wesley Hammond. July 17, 1874. Copy. 1 p.
---- Letter to Fred Hartje. May 31, 1871. Copy. 2 pp.
---- Letter to J. W. Haskins. September 9, 1881. Copy. 2 pp.
---- Three letters to Henry G. Hay. February 26, 1871-June 8, 1885. Copies. 15 pp.
---- Letter to George Hearst. October 19, 1874. Copy. 2 pp.
---- Letter to Nathaniel P. Hill. January 28, 1882. Draft. 2 pp.
---- Two letters to Hill and Hammill, St. Louis. May 8, 1874, October 17, [1885?]. Copies. 3 pp.
---- Letter to E. F. Honey. May 8, 1871. Copy. 2 pp.
---- Letter to H. H. Houghton. August 15, 1872. Copy. 1 p.
---- Letter to Andrew J. Houston. March 4, 1882. Copy. 1 p.
---- Letter to Andrew A. Humphreys. February 1, 1881. Copy. 2 pp.
---- Two letters to Frank Johnston. May 28, 1881, April 7, 1882. Copies. 6 pp.
---- Letter to Pat Kerwin. May 28, 1881. Copy. 2 pp.
---- Letter to Thomas L. Kimball. May 17, 1885. Copy. 2 pp.
---- Letter to John W. Kingman. June 14, 1874. Copy. 2 pp.
---- Three letters to Webster B. Lanphere. December 3, 1872- September 24, 1874. Drafts. 3 pp.
---- Two letters to Hiram Leffingwell. September 26, October 13, 1856, and a receipt, June 1, 1856, witnessed by C. S. Carpenter. Copies. 3 pp.
---- Letter to President Lincoln. April 11, 1861. Draft. 1 p.
---- Letter to [E.] Livigneur. September 28, 1877. Copy. 1 p.
---- Letter to J. F. Long. April 1, 1875. Draft. 3 pp.
---- Six letters to Frank G. Macomber. March 28, 1880-August 2, 1884. Copies. 22 pp.
---- Four letters to James Morrissey. June 20-July 23, 1874. Copies. 8 pp.
---- Letter to Henry A. Morrow. June 20, 1874. Copy. 1 p.
---- Five letters to Edward Page. September 30, 1881-July 2, 1886. Copies. 8 pp.
---- Letter to George Pierson. June 7, 1881. Copy. 2 pp.
---- Letter to William G. Provines. May 20, 1874. Copy. 1 p.
---- Letter to his father, Charles Reed. June 4, 1843. 2 pp.
---- Letter to his brother, Charles Reed, Jr. February 2 [-8], 1833. 4 pp.
---- Letter and telegram to his nephew Charles J. Reed. February 25, 1871, April 29, 1875. 2 pp.
---- Letter to his nephew, Alfred M. Rogers. June 25, 1886. Copy. 1 p.
---- Four letters to his nephew, Henry Munro Rogers. January 6, 1872- January 3, 1884. 17 pp.
---- Three letters to his brother-in-law, John H. Rogers. July 21- October 4, 1860. 8 pp.
---- Letter to his niece, Lucy Rogers. August 26, 1886. 4 pp.
---- Letter to Frederick Salomon. January [1881?]. Draft. 1 p.
---- Letter to Thomas A. Scott. January 27, 1881. Draft. 1 p.
---- Two letters to Seay and Kiskaddon. August 9, September 1, 1874. Drafts. 4 pp.
---- Letter to James Shields. July 12, 1845. Draft. 1 p.
---- Letter to D. K. Sickles. November 2, 1883. Draft. 3 pp.
---- Letter to Sickles and Randall. October 8, 1883. Draft. 2 pp.
---- Order on Dr. R. P. Simmons. November 18, 1841. 1 p.
---- Three letters to Oliver H. Smith. December 6, 1841-January 17, 1842. Copies. 4 pp.
---- Letter to W. R. Steele. April 22, 1873. Copy. 2 pp.
---- Letter to L. C. Stevens. February 26, 1871. Copy. 2 pp.
---- Letter to Charles H. Thirlwell. February 7, 1882. Copy. 1 p.
---- Letter to Lyon G. Tyler. April 21, 1886. Draft. 6 pp.
---- Letter to U.S. Congress, Judiciary Committee. April 22, [1886]. Draft. 2 pp.
---- Nine letters to President Grant. May 20, 1873-June 7, 1885. Drafts or copies. 16 pp.
---- Six letters to President Tyler. November 18, 1841- February 28, 1842. Drafts. 13 pp.
---- Letter to the U.S. Senate. December 15, 1841. Endorsed: "27 Cong. 2 Sess. Ex. Memorial of Silas Reed, with memorials from sundry persons of Illinois, Missouri & Iowa praying that injunction of secrecy be removed from his nomination, documents on file, &c. 1841, Dec 20. read and ordered to lie on the table. Dec. 30 resumed & referred to select committee ... Jan 25, report made & ordered to be printed in confidence for the use of the senate. Feb. 8. report & resolutions considered and agreed to, which grants leave to withdraw these memorials. Rec. Dec. 20." 1 p.
---- Memorials to the Senate of the United States. 9 printed forms signed by citizens of Davenport, Iowa; Hancock and Henderson Counties, Mo.; Madison County, Ill.; Peoria, Ill.; Rock Island, Ill.; Winnebago & Lee Counties, Ill.; St. Louis, Mo.; and by editors and proprietors of newspapers of St. Louis. 9 pp.
---- Memorandum of the memorials of July 8 to September 25, [1841] with a list of the signers in Reed's hand. 5 pp. With two copies of the printed report of the Senatorial Committee, Report: The Select Committee to Whom Were Referred the Memorials of Silas Reed, with Memorials from Sundry Persons ... Have Had the Same under Consideration, and Submit the Following Report ... (27th Congress, 2d Session, Confidential, Executive, No. 1, January 25, 1842). 5 pp.
---- Draft of a memorial "To the Honorable, the Senate and House of Representatives of the U.S. of America, in Congress Assembled," presenting his claim for compensation for the condemnation, in 1872, of his Olive Street property in St. Louis for a site for a post office and custom house, with memoranda and notes concerning the case [1874]. 29 pp.
---- Letter to Judge Robert Wash. October 18, 1841. Copy. 1 p. With a two-page draft of a letter about Judge Wash intended for publication in a newspaper.
---- Letter to Daniel Webster. August 20, 1841. Copy. 1 p.
---- Letter to L. B. Woodsides. August 8, 1874. Copy. 2 pp.
[Allen, William S.] Extract from a letter from the editor of the St. Louis Evening Gazette, January 3, 1842. Copy by Reed. 1 p.
Anthony, Arthur Cox. Seven letters to his mother. June 30, 1884- August 7, 1886. 29 pp.
---- 42 letters to his grandfather, Silas Reed. January 4, 1878- July 7, 1886. 169 pp.
Anthony, Clara James Reed (Mrs. Nathan). Three letters to her husband. May 9, 1870-February 6, 1880. 18 pp.
---- 13 letters to her father, Silas Reed. June 21, 1870- May 27, 1886. 42 pp.
---- 24 letters to her mother. [August 22? 1863]-November 16, 1885. 82 pp., 7 postcards.
Anthony, Nathan. 14 letters to his wife. August 11, 1864- February 6, 1880. 53 pp.
---- 56 letters and a telegram to his father-in-law, Dr. Reed. October 10, 1866-August 20, 1880. 153 pp.
---- Seven letters to Mrs. Reed. August 31, 1872- September 11, 1874. 15 pp.
Anthony, Nathan, Jr. Five letters to his grandfather, Dr. Reed. March 24, 1878-January 10, 1885. 11 pp.
Anthony, Silas Reed. Three letters and a postcard to his mother. August 5, 1881-November 15, 1885. 13 pp.
---- 49 letters to his grandfather, Dr. Reed. April 26, 1868- August 31, 1886. 209 pp.
---- 33 letters to his grandmother. January 21, 1871- October 2, 1886. 56 pp.
Babson, John James. Letter to his brother-in-law, Dr. Reed. October 22, 1873. 4 pp.
Bailey F. C. Letter to James Moffat. January 4, 1886. Copy. 1 p.
Barnes, Joseph K. Circular No. 21. Instructions, Washington, October 1, 1863. Signed by Joseph K. Barnes, A.S.G. 3 pp.
Betts, Thomas. Two letters to Reed. May [2], 18, 1872. Copies. 3 pp.
Biser, Charles T. Agreement, signed also by Reed. May 26, 1882. 2 pp.
Blair, Montgomery. Letter to Thomas H. Benton. November 18, 1841. Copy. 1 p.
Brown, Arthur. Letter to Reed. November 21, 1884. Copy. 2 pp.
Brown, Walter C. Letter to John C. New. September 24, 1875. Copy. 2 pp.
Burdett, Samuel S. Letter to Reed. October 8, 1875. Signature only. 1 p.
Cady, C. C. Letter to Thomas Ewing. August 29, 1841. Copy. 1 p.
---- Two letters to the President of the United States. August 20, November 18, 1841. Copies. 2 pp.
---- Letter to Daniel Webster. August 20, 1841. Copy. 1 p.
Chambers, William. Letter to Thomas H. Benton. November 9, 1841. Copy. 1 p.
Clark, John B. Letter to Reed. July 23, 1841. 1 p.
Coe, Henry I. Letter to Reed. June 12, 1874. Copy. 2 pp.
Cushing, Caleb. Letter to Reed. December 17, 1841. 1 p.
Dallas County, Texas, District Court. Summons to Reed to appear in court, June 9, 1878, to answer petition of Francis Fox. Signed May 31, 1878, by W. A. Harwood, Clerk. Printed form.
Daugherty, John M. Letter to Reed. November 15, 1869. 1 p.
Delano, Columbus. Three letters to Reed. June 19, 1873- September 5, 1875. 5 pp.
Delano, John S. Letter to Reed. October 14, 1872. Signature only. 1 p.
Dement, P. B. Letter to Reed. December 18, 1885. Signature only. 1 p.
Dinnies, J. C. Letter to Thomas Ewing. August 20, 1841. Copy. 2 pp.
Droger, Henry C. Letter to Reed. February 1, 1873. 1 p.
Drummond, Willis. Order to Reed to turn over the surveyor general's office to Hiram Latham. March 29, 1873. Printed form. 1 p.
---- Instructions to registers and receivers. June 30, 1873. Printed form. 1 p.
---- Letter to Dr. Reed. February 2, 1881. 1 p.
Eads, James B. Letter to Edward Bates. March 28, 1861. Copy by Eads. 2 pp.
Eitzen, Charles D. Letter to Reed. November 25, 1874. 1 p.
Elliott, Richard S. Letter to Reed, with Olive Street property account. November 2, 1856. 4 pp.
Ervin, W. C. Agreement with Mrs. Reed about the Carrie Shields mine, signed by Ervin and Mrs. Reed. August 30, 1871. 3 pp.
Ewing, Thomas. Letter to Reed. August 30, 1841. Signature only. 1 p.
Farrar, Benjamin. Letter to F. P. Blair, Jr. March 25, 1861. 2 pp.
Ferguson, Daniel. Letter to Reed. December 1, 1841. 1 p.
Field, A. P. Letter to Caleb Cushing. October 29, 1841. Copy. 1 p.
---- Letter to Daniel Webster. October 29, 1841. 1 p.
Field, Kate. Letter to Reed. May 18, 1886. 2 pp.
Fletcher, Thomas C. Letter to W. H. Austin. December 23, 1876. 1 p.
Foglesong, George D. Two letters to Reed. April 22, 23, 1873. 4 pp.
Garnsey, C. A. Letter to Reed. October [25], 1841. 3 pp.
Garnsey, Daniel G. Letter to Reed. October 30, 1841. 3 pp.
Glafcke, Herman. Two letters to Reed. January 2, April 23, 1873. 3 pp.
Gorlinski, Robert. Letter to Reed. September 2, 1886. 1 p.
Gould, Philander. Letter to Thomas Ewing. August 21, 1841. Copy. 2 pp.
Hall, J. W. Letter to J. T. Moorehead. August 20, 1841. Copy with a note to Thomas Ewing added by Reed. 2 pp.
Hammond, J. Wesley. Letter to Reed. December 29, 1873. 4 pp.
---- Memorandum of understanding between Hammond and Mr. Marion. May 1874. 1 p.
Harlow, Lewis D. Letter to Reed. December 10, 1863. 1 p.
Harrison, C. R. Letter to Reed. June 20, 1884. 2 pp.
Harrison, George W. Letter to Reed. July 8, 1841. 2 pp.
Hay, Henry G. 27 letters to Reed. November 14, 1864- August 19, 1886. 58 pp.
---- Two letters to Mrs. Reed. November 10, [1872], November 2, 1885. 7 pp.
---- Letter to H. M. Rogers. June 27, 1882. 3 pp.
Hearst, George. Power of attorney to Reed, February 1, 1873, witnessed by James Mason, F. I. Thibault, Henry C. Droger, with affidavit by Thibault. Recorded, March 5, 1873, by Michael Bauer. 3 pp.
Hearst, Phoebe Apperson (Mrs. George). Letter to Clara Anthony. [May? 1886.] 3 pp.
---- Letter to Dr. Reed. May 15, 1886. 2 pp.
---- Ten letters to Mrs. Reed. March 21, 1872- [June? 1886]. 55 pp.
Henderson, D. R. Letter to Reed. September 11, 1867. 1 p.
Henderson, Malcolm. Letter to Allen & Gaston. August 30, 1877. Endorsed: "Accepted, W. H. Gaston, Pres. D. & W. R.R. Co." 1 p.
---- Contract for financing the construction of the Dallas and Wichita Railroad, September 12, 1878. Signed by Henderson and Reed. 2 pp.
---- Agreement, July 3, 1879. Signed by Henderson and Reed. 4 pp.
---- Statement of claims and expenditures covered by the contract of September 12, 1878. Draft by Reed. 5 pp.
Herrick, H. J. Letter to Reed. September 22, 1883. With note added by Josephine Steffens. 1 p.
Herron, J. H. Letter to Reed. April 3, 1873. 1 p.
Houghton, H. H. Letter to Reed. April 9, 1872. 3 pp.
Houston, Andrew Jackson. Letter to H. M. Rogers. December 31, 1881. 2 pp.
---- Two receipts to Reed for payments in cases of Allen & Nettleton vs. Dallas and Wichita Railroad, and Reed vs. Harris. November 18, 1880. 2 pp.
Huntington, E. M. Three letters to Reed. July 27-November 22, 1841. 4 pp.
Hussey, J. B. Two letters to Reed. October 11, 13, 1879. Copies in Reed's letters to his wife, October 14, 15.
James, Clara Rogers (Mrs. Edwin). Letter to her sister, Mrs. Reed. April 28, 1838. With noted added by Mr. James. 1 p.
James, Edwin. Three letters to his sister-in-law, Mrs. Reed. January 13, 1859-September 18, 1860. 12 pp.
Johnston, Alex. Letter to Reed. March 22, 1871. 1 p.
Johnston, Frank. Three letters and a postcard to Reed. September 21, 1882-August 11, 1886. One a copy. 3 pp.
Kimball, Nathan. Letter to Reed. June 6, 1874. 1 p.
Kingman, John W. Three letters to Reed. April 22-June 5, 1873. One a copy. 13 pp.
Kinney, George N. Letter to Reed. December 12, 1841. 1 p.
Kiskaddon, J. C. Letter to A. J. Seay. February 5, 1881. Copy. 4 pp.
Krone, William. Letter to Reed. December 6, 1871. 1 p.
Lanphere, Webster B. 21 letters to Reed. August 15, 1873- October 16, 1874. 90 pp.
Latham, Hiram. Letter to Reed. April 14, 1873. 1 p.
Lawless, L. E. Letter to Colonel T. H. Benton. November 15, 1841. Copy. 1 p.
Leffingwell, Hiram W., U.S. Marshal. Notices of bankruptcy of Henry I. Coe. June 18, 1878. Copy. 1 p.
Lightner, J. H. Letter to Montgomery Blair. March 26, 1861. 1 p.
McDermont, C. Letter to Reed. December 10, 1863. 1 p.
McFarland, N. C. Letter to Reed. April [26], 1882, signature only, enclosing a copy of a letter to him from A. Bell, acting secretary, Department of the Interior. August 8, 1880. 12 pp.
McKee, William. Letter to Reed. April 10, 1873. 2 pp.
---- Letter to the President of the United States. May 2, 1873. Signed by William McKee, Henry T. Blow, C. W. Ford. Copy. 2 pp.
Macomber, Clara Elizabeth Robison (Mrs. F. G.) "Belle." Eight letters to her grandfather, Dr. Reed. October 30, 1867-June 27, [1886]. 39 pp.
Mallory, Thomas H. Letter to Reed. February 24, 1875. 1 p.
Matthews, Leonard, and Whittaker, Edwards. Judgment vs. Silas Reed, Circuit Court, City of St. Louis, February 17, 1879. With assignments to James L. Blair by Matthews and Whittaker, August 1, 1879; and to Hugh A. Crawford by Blair, October 2, 1879. Certified, a true copy, by Charles F. Vogel, Clerk, with seal, October 3, 1879. Recorded, October 4, 1879, W. L. Lyles, Clerk. 2 pp.
Miller, John G. Letter to Governor Gilmer. January 7, 1841 [i.e., 1842]. Copy. 1 p.
---- Letter to Reed. February 1, 1842. 4 pp.
Missouri Land Company. Letter to George K. Budd. January 10, 1866. Signed by T. S. Rutherfurd, Thomas E. Souper, H. I. Coe. Copy. 2 pp.
---- Agreement to sell land to Reed. December 29, 1865. Signed by Rutherfurd, Souper and Coe. 2 pp.
Missouri Smelting and Mineral Lands Company. Mr. Coe's statement of assets and liabilities, August 27, 1869. 2 pp.
---- List of stockholders. St. Louis, May 11, 1875. Copy. 1 p.
---- Agreement, Silas Reed with William A. Shepard, August 4, 1876. Signed before J. L. Harrison, and continued to March 10, 1877. 3 pp.
---- Agreement to purchase land from Reed, March 7, 1877, signed by Shepard. 1 p.
---- Agreement regarding price for land in Dent and Phelps Counties, March 10, 1877, signed by Shepard. 1 p.
Moore, John M. Letter to Reed. October 23, 1841. 2 pp.
Morrow, Henry A. Letter to Reed. April 29, 1873. 2 pp.
Newberry, J. S. Letter to Reed. April 8, 1881. 3 pp.
O'Connor, W. F. Letter to Isaac S. Coe. April 17, 1872, with added note to Reed from Thomas Betts. Copy. 2 pp.
Page, Edward. Four letters to Reed. September 16, 1883-August 20, 1886. One a copy. 4 pp.
---- Agreement with William F. James, November 5, 1881, signed by Page and George W. Emery, attorney for James. Copy. 2 pp.
Page, Henry. Letter to Reed. November 2, 1882. 3 pp.
Paschall, Nathaniel. Letter to President Tyler. August 19, 1841. Copy. 2 pp.
Post, M. Hayward. Letter to Reed. October 12, 1872, with noted added by T. M. Post. 3 pp.
Post, T. M. Letter to Reed. September 25, 1872. Signature only. 3 pp.
Provines, William G. Letter to Reed. January 18, 1875. 3 pp.
Ray, James M. Letter to Reed. April 2, 1873. 1 p.
Reams, Jon T. Agreement to sell land in Franklin County, Mo., September 20, 1859. Signed by Reams and Reed. 2 pp.